Germain Arturo Duran Torres

Jersey City, NJ 07302 · (917) 650-6955

arturodurantorres@gmail.com · <u>GitHub</u> · <u>Blog</u> · <u>Portfolio</u> · <u>LinkedIn</u> Fully Work Authorized Indefinitely · No Visa Sponsorship Required

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Engineer with 5+ years' experience in software development and solutions engineering. Passionate about technology, innovation and providing clients with solutions. My extended strengths beyond what's outlined within my resume are my dependability, dedication, determination and Spanish fluency.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming languages (JavaScript, React, Node.js, Java, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS) Database (SQL, Postgres).
- Git, Salesforce, JIRA, Figma, E-commerce, Magento, Data Entry, Ad Tech, Mobile SDK.
- OS (Windows, Linux, Mac OS), Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook).

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Full Stack Web Development, Immersive Software Engineering, Flatiron School, New York, NY Introduction to JAVA Programming Course, New York University, New York, NY

10/2018 – 02/2019

02/2018 - 04/2018

PROJECT BASED WORK

TriPacking - GitHub repo | Demo | Portfolio

Application that allows users to create, edit, delete trips and suitcases with the feature of adding/organizing belongings

- Developed a Rails API backend with endpoints for users, trips, belongings and suitcases; enabled full CRUD for trips, suitcases and belongings and incorporated Cloudinary API to enable image uploads.
- Implemented user interface employing React/Redux and JavaScript with Materialize CSS for styling.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Solutions Engineer

Taboola, New York, United States

01/2021- present

- Provide a high-level of technical service and support to customers by implementing Taboola's products such as: feed, video units, widgets, etc.
- Assist in the creation and modification of custom user interfaces and logic for Taboola's recommendation modules.
- Collaborate with the business teams throughout the company and work directly with external customers' product and technical teams to successfully implement and launch Taboola's products.
- Perform in-depth troubleshooting, including DB analysis and reading system logs to identify and solve complex issues.
- Setup and run A/B tests for customers in order to optimize performance.
- Management of numerous tasks (via Salesforce & Jira) and resources in parallel, prioritizing customer requirements and requests. Help publishers promote their content and monetize their sites in an efficient manner.
- Write technical notes and documentation to be utilized by others on the team.
- As subject matter expert (SME) for mobile SDK integrations, provide ongoing training to the PS team to identify product bugs and minimize R&D escalations.

Support Engineer 10/2019 – 01/2021

BaubleBar Inc, New York, United States

- Tested and debugged issues related to the deployment, and ongoing support of BaubleBar products.
- Managed all tickets via JIRA from marketing, creative and production teams and external integration partners.
- Documented, reported and provided quality assurance in the engineering team through confluence pages.
- Updated homepage, banners, footer, footer pages and navigation bar across Baublebar.com.
- Created transactional emails templates and sent them to customers through Sendgrid API.
- Conducted internal and external follow-up on issues to verify issue resolution and ensure customer satisfaction.
- Provided API support to integration partners to ensure the leverage of use of APIs
 <u>Full stack technologies:</u> JIRA, HTML, CSS, Node.js, Figma, Magento, CircleCI, Mailtrap, PHP, Confluence pages, API
 troubleshooting, Slack, SQL.

Software Engineering Consultant

04/2019 - 05/2019

Trainee MThree Consulting, New York, United States

- Engaged in DevOps principles, focusing on key elements that deliver business value.
- Trained in Bash/Shell Scripting using a Unix system, while covering the basics of Unix commands.
- Acquired SQL skills to create, edit, read and delete tables containing large amounts of data.
- Trained in Java and JavaScript and developed skilled in full stack development.

Junior Consulting Engineer

04/2015 - 08/2018

ORACLE and ITBC Group, Caracas, Venezuela

- Supported production in project CRM, solving a high volume of tickets in order to offer optimal service in the Oracle product acquired by the client Banesco (the largest commercial private bank in Venezuela).
- Monitored the database load daily through SQL to verify the bank's operations were executed correctly.
- Created weekly reports for the client, explaining each incident and how it was resolved.
- Utilized WebLogic and Linux for the deployment of JAVA applications for Corporation Digital (one of the leading telecommunications services companies in Venezuela).

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Telecommunications Engineering

2010 - 2015